### Download this resume: https://amazingandyyy.com/resume/

# **Andy Chen**

Rich full product life-cycle engineer/design experience. Initial product with production-ready codes and helping many others. I believe the philosophy of "learning by doing" and "the best way to learn is to teach." amazingandyyy@gmail.com (408) 431-3552 (CA Time) github.com/amazingandyyy linkedin.com/in/amazingandyyy/

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## <u>Vechain Community</u>, Open Source— Founder and Project *lead* May 2018 - PRESENT

- Contributed to vechain/thor, vechain/thorify, and other Vechain open source projects on github.
- Initiative multiples demos about DApp, integrated with hyperledger, dockernized-DevOps for the dev. community, for the open source community
- Plan to initiate a Vechain Node Observation app and Vechain Full Node hosting service to the community.

## <u>Ventured International Inc.</u>, San Francisco — *Chief Product* Officer July 2017 - April 2018 (Failed)

- Implemented TDD with Jest to engineer production-ready smart contracts in Solidity and deployed to Ethereum Live Network with Truffle framework.
- Launched VentureCoin(<u>VCN</u>), implement ERC20 token and a 3 month crowdsale on Nov.
- Launched company website, whitepaper and branding designs. A reference to my article on how we build our product (<a href="here">here</a>.

### <u>Yeah Education Group</u>, Berkeley — *Chief Technical Officer*

Dec. 2015 - April 2017 (alive with 2M AR)

- Led a software development team to iterate four versions of the full software architect and application in MERN stack, and built over 50 internal/external endpoints.
- Deployed the application to various PaaS platforms to serve users across US and Mainland China.
- The software solution successfully scaled the business 20 times to a 1M annual revenue (2016) and led into Berkeley Skydeck incubator cohort in April, 2017.

### <u>Andysign Studio</u>, Mountain View — Software Developer

Oct 2014 - Sept. 2016

- Constructed freelancing website and branding design service.
   Launched 8 websites including Groove Trend and Swallet visited by 10K visitors daily.
- Implemented A/B testing for UI elements, heatmap analysis on user behaviors and website SEO leading to a 100% increase of traffic in the initial month.

#### **TEACHING/MENTORSHIP**

NodeSchool Oakland and San Francisco Chapter Served as regular monthly mentor in Nodeschool Oakland

Reactathon, 2017 Served as mentor at the hackathon held by the Real World React organization

Active Medium Contributor
Developed and share a series
of tutorials on web
development,
blockchain-related smart
contract, devOps and software
design topics

### OPEN SOURCE CONTRIBUTION

nodejs/node, submitted
PR#10092[merged] and
#10093[merged] to update
and improve testing
environment

dawsbot/mailto, submitted PR#3[Closed], PR#4[merged] to resolve multiple issues and optimize key features

ConsenSys/Token-Factory, submitted PR#54[Opend] to update error handling

**Vechain/thorify,** update documentation and propose new thorify features

#### **EDUCATION**

## **University of California, Berkeley,** Berkeley — Bachelor's of Science, Cognitive Science

June 2016 - July 2018

Courses: Data Visualization, Blockchain for Developers, Computer Human Interface, Cognitive Science, Linguistics, Data Structure, Discrete Math.

## **Foothill College**, Los Altos Hill — Associate's Degree, Anthropology

Aug 2014 - June 2016

Earned Excellent Anthropology Student recognition by Foothill College and served as Research Assistant of Applied Anthropology Department and participated in the Ireland Archaeology Program (2015 summer).

## **Shanghai Jiao Tong University,** Shanghai, China — Dropped out, Economics and Finance

Aug 2012 - June 2014

Dropped out from SJTU Antai College of Economics & Management in 2014 then decided to go to California to pursuing the American Dream.

#### **PROJECTS**

### <u>Leptin</u> — A PoW cryptocurrency implement in Nodejs

Designed and Built a whole cryptocurrency in nodejs with leveraging power of WebRTC, LevelDB, hyperlogs to build a peer-to-peer blockchain which even implement Proof-of-work, secp256k1 and dynamical difficulty.

### Etherbrite — An eventbrite-like DApp.

Built a DApp in Solidity, TruffleJS, Web3js and React/Redux. From deploying events on smart contract to register user and check user in.

### <u>VRPlayer</u> — A video player built with ReactVR and openGL

Built this video player on the fist of ReactVR's launch, with a focus on the interaction details of user experience in virtual reality.

## <u>Serperpay</u> — A fintech app to streamline the multiple-installments payment process.

A consumer and business-facing web app that integrated with Stripe payment API and CronJob to make monthly payment easy and flexible. Deployed to EC2 and pitched at the 2016 Plug&Play Fintech Demo Day.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Front-End: HTML/SCSS/JS, React, Angular, Webpack, proficient in RWD

Fullstack: MEAN, MEAN 2.0,

MERN, RoR

Backend: Golang, python

DevOps: Docker, TravisCI, AWS(VPC, EC2, S3), GCP, IBM Bluemix(hyperledger)

#### **HACKATHONS/AWARDS**

H4YT Hackathon 2018 - Top 3 nomination by Cosmos for building <u>Celadon</u>, a lotionjs middleware donating money to help our environment.

LAUNCH Hackathon 2016 - 1st place of Uber Challenge [2016] for building Teleport, an advertisement site that magically deliver customers to your door.

AT&T Mobile App Hackathon
- 1st Coding House Challenge
[2016] for building Masty, a
livestream app as
simultaneously a trading
marketplace for streamers.

AT&T IoT Hackathon - Best Mobile App and IoT Solution Overall[2015] for building Connect, an radio player controlled by a gesture controller, Myo.